# **RYAN JED TENAJA**

Permanent Home Address: Punta Baluarte, Lower Camanjac DumagueteCity, Negros Oriental M: 09778236093

E: ryanjedt@gmail.com



## **Career Summary & Objective:**

Mr. Tenaja started his career at Fluor 3 years ago as a material expeditor that handled complex mechanical packages. His levels of responsibility include analysis, reviewing and distributing supplier production, work, and shipment schedules in adjacent to project schedule; conferring with department supervisors to determine progress of work and completion dates; compiling reports on progress of work, inventory levels, costs, and production problems; and confirming and expediting of critical materials.

#### **Job Experiences:**

#### **Fluor Daniel**

Procurement, Material Expeditor TGU Tower, 5<sup>th</sup> floor, I.T. Park, Lahug Cebu City May 2014-Sep 2017

Responsible for monitoring, meeting, and coordinating with the suppliers to ensure timely delivery, reporting and mitigating of delays, expediting of critical documents from both Fluor and suppliers, expediting of critical packages, coordinating supplier to engineering issue resolutions, coordination with logistics for shipping, and prompt reporting to the project team.

Marathon BT3
USLG Project Tier 3
6/2017-Present Houston, United States
Mechanical and Bulk Packages

Sasol Ltd.
Lake Charles Chemical Project
3/2016 – Present Louisiana, United States
Control Systems (Control Valves)
Procurement Function: Close Out

Dow Chemical Co.

DOW Gulfstream Program (LHC9)
6/2014 - 2/2016 Freeport, Texas, United States

Mechanical and Control Systems Packages (Heat Exchangers, Control Valves)

JPMorgan Chase & Co.

**Business Process Operations** 

E-bloc Tower 3, I.T. Park, Lahug Cebu City

April-July 2013

From transferring funds to problem solving, Telephone Bankers answer, gather information, evaluate, and assist customers in their banking needs.

# **Government Service Insurance System**

Practicum 2M (Actual Business Exposure – On the Job Training)

DumagueteCity, Negros Oriental

June - October 2012

Assigned to the collections and finance department, the trainee was tasked to file, answer calls, and assist the department head on handling beneficiaries.

## **Educational Background:**

Tertiary: Bachelor of Business Administration- Major in Management (2009-2013)

SillimanUniversity, DumagueteCity, Negros Oriental

Secondary: St. PaulUniversity (2005-2009)

DumagueteCity, Negros Oriental

Primary: ABCLearningCenter (2002 – 2005)

DumagueteCity, Negros Oriental

SPED Center for Fast Learners (1999 –2002)

DumagueteCity, Negros Oriental

### **Skills:**

Microsoft Office Computer Applications- (MS Word 2010, MS Excel 2007, MS Power Point)
Supply Chain Management (Expediting, Purchasing, Logistics) – Fluor Daniels
Customer Relations – JP Morgan Chase
Telephone Etiquette – JP Morgan Chase

## **Trainings and Seminars:**

Material Management Purchasing Effective Field Material Management Logistics: Import, Export Compliance Contract Management

**Negotiation: The Negotiation Process** 

### **Professional Affiliations:**

- 1. Graduates Advancing on Professionalism, Socials Chair, Year 2017
- 2. Fluor Employee Relations Committee, Socials Vice-Chair, Year 2016
- 3. Fluor Community Relations, Fund Raising Committee, Year 2015
- 4. Silliman Junior Business Executives, Member, Year 2009-2013

5. College Student Council, Chairperson- Committee on Programs, Year 2012-2013

## **Character References:**

1. Jhey Bernas – Expediting Functional Lead Fluor Daniels Inc. Philippines

5<sup>th</sup> Floor, TGU Tower, I.T.Park, Lahug Cebu City

M: +63 917 325 7715

2. Albert Keith Dominguito – Supply Chain Department Manager Fluor Daniels Inc. Philippines

 $\mathbf{5}^{\text{th}}$  Floor, TGU Tower, I.T.Park, Lahug Cebu City

M: +63 998 590 0104

3. Atty. Gloria G. Funtalan- College Dean

College of Business Administration Silliman University, Dumaguete City

M: +632 09273140944

I hereby certify to the best of my knowledge and belief that the above mentioned information are true and correct.

\_\_\_\_ Ryan Jed C. Tenaja